A Guide to the William H. Stein papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA127
Rockefeller Archive Center
William H. Stein papers, Rockefeller University Faculty
1937-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Stein, William H.
FA127
35 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
William Stein, whose work focused on the relationships between the chemical structures of proteins with their biological functions, was born in New York City in 1911. He was educated at Exeter Academy and Harvard University, graduating with a B.S. degree in 1933. It was while he was pursuing his doctoral studies at Columbia University that he first became associated with The Rockefeller University, then known as the Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. He began as a volunteer in the laboratory of chemist Max Bergmann. After he graduated from Columbia in 1938, he was employed as an assistant in Bergmann's laboratory. In 1952, Dr. Stein became a member of the Institute and then later a Professor at the University. Although stricken with Guillain-Barre Syndrome in 1969, he continued to do his research up to the time of his death in 1980.
Over the years, Dr. Stein worked with colleagues to develop chromatographic procedures for the separation and quantitative determination of amino acids. These procedures proved very valuable by facilitating the analysis of amino acids as well as other substances found in such biological fluids as blood plasma, tissue extracts, and urine. Dr. Stein collaborated extensively with his fellow Rockefeller colleague, Dr. Stanford Moore. In 1959, for the first time, Drs. Stein and Moore succeeded to decipher the complete chemical structure of ribonuclease. Together, they developed special scientific instrumentation related to their research, including automatic amino acid analyzers and automatic fraction collectors. These types of equipment later became commercially available and widely used.
In 1972, Drs. Stein and Moore were jointly awarded the Nobel Prize in Chemistry for investigations on the structure and activity of ribonuclease. They also shared a number of other awards. In 1964, they received the Electrophoresis and Chromatography Award from the American Chemical Society in recognition of the analytical methods they developed. That organization also presented them with the Theodore William Richard Medal in 1972 for their contributions to protein chemistry.
Dr. Stein frequently contributed to numerous scientific periodicals. He was chairman of the editorial committee of the American Society of Biological Chemists (1958-1961) and the editor of the Journal of Biological Chemistry (1968-1971). Dr. Stein was active in a number of scientific societies. In 1960 he was elected to the National Academy of Sciences and was named a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
A dedicated teacher, William Stein delivered, along with colleagues Lyman Craig and Stanford Moore, a lecture entitled "On Separating Things" at the Rockefeller Institute in 1961. This lecture series was repeated in Boston in 1962. The lectures, which focused on the techniques of physical and chemical separations on which much of modern biological science rests, were given to a specially selected group of high school students. At various points in his career, Dr. Stein was a Harvey Lecturer, a Phillips Lecturer at Haverford College, and an American-Swiss Foundation Fellow and Lecturer.
Arrangement note
Arranged in chronological and alphabetical order.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 450 St34
Conditions Governing Access note
Access to this collection is restricted pending permission from Rockefeller University.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: personal files, correspondence, lectures, manuscripts, notes, slides, and audio tapes.
Electrophoresis; Medical sciences; Amino acids; Medical research; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Biochemistry; Blood; Moore, Stanford; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Rockefeller University
- Personal Files, 1972-1980; 1; 0.44 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes biographical and Nobel Prize material.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Biography and Bibliography (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificate of Gift (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Nobel Prize 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Obituary Items (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs and Newsclippings (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Richards Medal 1972 (includes tape of address by Dr. Westheimer at ceremony) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1937-1980; 2; 4.84 Cubic Feet
  Includes primarily professional correspondence.
  Arranged in alphabetical and then in chronological order.
  - ["A"] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Association of Cereal Chemists (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - American Chemical Society (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - American Society of Brewing Chemists (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anfinsen, Christian B. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - ["B"] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bailey, J. Leggett (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bean-Benjamin (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bennett-Bloch (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Blomback-Bruice (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bohak, Zvi (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Books (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Borsook, Henry (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Brigham, M.P. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Brenner, Max (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Buchanan (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Burke-Butler (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Calbiochem-Chargaff (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Carter, H.E. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Catley, Brian John (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cherkasky-Claude (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cohen-Collman (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Colowick-Curtis (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Crampton, C.F. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Crestfield, Arthur M. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Datta-DeRay (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - DeSnuelle-Duty (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Dopheide, T.A.A. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Eagle-Elms (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Edelman, Gerald M. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Edmundson, Jr., Allen B. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Elsas (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Elsevier-Evans (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ettre, L.S. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Farber-Fisher (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ferdinand, William (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fishman-Frey (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Frimpter (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fruchter, Mrs. R.G. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fruton, J.S. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Garcia, Ghiretti (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Ghose-Gottschalk (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Grazi-Gunnery (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gunsalus-Gutte (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Harte, Robert A., 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Harte, Robert A., 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Hamilton, P.B. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Handler, Philip (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Haidemenakis-Hayden (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Head-Hill (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Hirs-Hurwitz (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hofmann, Klaus (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Holt, Allen (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Horecker, B.L. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ["I-J"] (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Jones, Glyn (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Kabat-Kay (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Kendrew, John C. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Kennedy-Knowles (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Kessler, Alexander (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Koch-Kupke (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - ["L"] (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Lindestrom-Lang Medal (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Ludblad, Robert L., 1 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ludblad, Robert L., 2 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ludblad, Robert L., 3 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Ludblad, Robert L., 4 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - McClure-Marks (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Marsh-Murachi (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Montefiore Hospital (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Moore, Stanford (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Moore, Stanford, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - National Academy of Sciences 1945 Conference (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Nemethy-Notre Dame (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Neuberger, Albert (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Neuman, N.P. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Neurath, Hans (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Ogston-Overberger (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Ota, Shoshi (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Page-Paulus (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Pearson-Phillips (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Photaki-Porter, K. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Porter, R.-Pusey (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Perlmann, Gertrude E. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rabin-Rawson (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Rasmussen, Howard (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Redlich-Ris (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Richards, F.M., 1 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Richards, F.M., 2 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Robbins-Roseman (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Rosenberg-Rutter (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Rohm & Haas Company (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Sacchi-Saunders (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Schachman-Scully (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Sela-Shedlovsky (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Schroeder, Walter A. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Shields-Slater (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Shook and Bingaman (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Skupin, J. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Smith, Emil L., 1 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Emil L., 2 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Smith-Stetten (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Smyth, Derek G. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Soviet Scientists, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Sternglaz, Rolf (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Stever-Synge (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Stroock, Dan (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Taborsky-Tuchman (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Tiselius, Arne (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Ubell-Utter (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Uziel, Mayo (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Vagelos-Von Hippel (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Wacker-Weinstein (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Weizmann-Williams (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Westheimer, Frank (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - White, Abraham (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Whitney Foundation (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Wiley & Sons, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Wolf-Wyman (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Woodford, F. Peter (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Yanari-Zinn (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Lecture Files, 1950-1969; 3; 4.4 Cubic Feet
  Includes lecture transcripts, notes and some correspondence.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by lecture topic and/or location.
  - Lectures: Summaries and Reading Lists, 1 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lectures: Summaries and Reading Lists, 2 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Syllabi for Harvard Lectures (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Lectures I - Introduction (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lectures II - Isolation of Proteins (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Lectures III - Separation Methods (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Lectures IV - Chromatography (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Lectures V - Prelude to Sequence Studies (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Lectures VI - Determining the Sequence of Amino Acid Residue in a Protein (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Lectures VII - Three Dimensional Structures (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Lectures VIII (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Lectures IX (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Lectures X (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Lectures XII (Box 14, Folder 3)
    *Lectures XI not included.
  - American Chemical Society (ACS), 1950 February-September (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - ACS Lecture, 1955 March 9; 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - ACS Lecture, 1955 March 9; 2 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - ACS Lecture September, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Brandeis University, 1967 November (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Brigham (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Brookhaven, 1960 June (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Brookhaven and Harvard, Lectures, Spring 1956; 1 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Brookhaven and Harvard, Lectures, Spring 1956; 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn Biology Lecture, 1953 January (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Calif. Trip, 1969; 1 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Calif. Trip, 1969; 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Chicago Lecture January, 1960; 1 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Chicago Lecture January, 1960; 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Christmas Lecture One, 1961; 1 of 4 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Christmas Lecture One, 1961; 2 of 4 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Lecture One, 1961; 3 of 4 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Christmas Lecture One, 1961; 4 of 4 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Christmas Lecture Five, 1961; 1 of 3 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Christmas Lecture Five, 1961; 2 of 3 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Christmas Lecture Five, 1961; 3 of 3 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Ciba Symposium London, 1952; 1 of 3 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Ciba Symposium London, 1952; 2 of 3 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Ciba Symposium London, 1952; 3 of 3 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Cold Spring Harbor Symposium, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - College of Physicians and Surgeons Bicentennial (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Column Chromatography - Northwestern University, 1950 February 6 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Copenhagen, 1969; 1 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Copenhagen, 1969; 2 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Copenhagen, 1969; 3 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Darwin Centennial Lecture, 1959 March; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Darwin Centennial Lecture, 1959 March; 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Duke Seminar, 1962; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Duke Seminar, 1962; 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Eli Lilly Lecture, 1961 May (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Federation Talk - Chicago, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Gordon Conference, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Gordon Conference, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Gordon Conference, 1961 June; 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Gordon Conference, 1961 June; 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Gordon Conference, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Gordon Conference, 1966; 1 of 3 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Gordon Conference, 1966; 2 of 3 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Gordon Conference, 1966; 3 of 3 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Gordon Conference, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Harvey Lecture, 1956; 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Harvey Lecture, 1956; 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - India Trip (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Insulin (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - International Congress of Biochemistry, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Isolation of Pure Amino Acids (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Israel, 1965; 1 of 4 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Israel, 1965; 2 of 4 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Israel, 1965; 3 of 4 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Israel, 1965; 4 of 4 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Italy, 1964; 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Italy, 1964; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - MIT Lecture, 1960 November (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Montreal Talk, 1954 October (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - NATO - Venice, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Orientation Lectures (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - P-Nitrophenyl Acetate (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Paris Symposium, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Pennsylvania Seminars, 1967 March (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Philip Shaffer Lecture, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Phillips Lecture, 1962; 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Phillips Lecture, 1962; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Pittsburgh Lecture, 1955 February 8 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Purdue-February, 1966; 1 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Purdue-February, 1966; 2 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Purdue-February, 1966; 3 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - RIMR Staff Meeting, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Rutgers-Princeton Seminar, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Seattle Talk April, 1955; 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Seattle Talk April, 1955; 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Starch Gel Studies (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Survey of Chemistry Panel, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Swiss Lectures, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Switzerland Trip, Fall 1956; 1 of 5 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Switzerland Trip, Fall 1956; 2 of 5 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Switzerland Trip, Fall 1956; 3 of 5 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Switzerland Trip, Fall 1956; 4 of 5 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Switzerland Trip, Fall 1956; 5 of 5 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Symposium Talk, 1956 April (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Tokyo, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Venice, 1967; 1 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Venice, 1967; 2 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Venice, 1967; 3 of 3 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Western Trip, Summer 1959 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Administrative Work, 1960-1974; 4; 6.6 Cubic Feet
  Includes correspondence and files with both professional and RU administrative bodies.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by name of organization.
  - Academic Council (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists (ASBC), 1 of 4 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 2 of 4 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 3 of 4 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - American Society of Biological Chemists, 4 of 4 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - ASBC Council, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - ASBC Bylaws, 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - ASBC Nominating Committee (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - ASBC Council, 1960; 1 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - ASBC Council, 1960; 2 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - ASBC Council, 1960; 3 of 3 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - ASBC Council, 1961; 1 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - ASBC Council, 1961; 2 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1959 January-June (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1959 July-December (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1960; 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1960; 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1961 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1962; 1 of 3 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1962; 2 of 3 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1962; 3 of 3 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1963 January-May; 1 of 3 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1963 January-May; 2 of 3 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1963 January-May; 3 of 3 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1963 June-December; 1 of 3 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1963 June-December; 2 of 3 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1963 June-December; 3 of 3 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1964; 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1964; 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1965; 1 of 3 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1965; 2 of 3 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1965; 3 of 3 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - ASBC Finance Committee, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Associated Universities (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Bronk (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Building and Grounds (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Budget, 1 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Budget, 2 of 2 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Departmental Affairs, 1 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Departmental Affairs, 2 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Division of Chemistry and Chemical Technology, 1 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Division of Chemistry and Chemical Technology, 2 of 2 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Committee on Biochemistry and Chemistry (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - FASEB (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Flinn-Safety (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Grant # GM-07256 Renewal, 1966; 1 of 2 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Grant # GM-07256 Renewal, 1966; 2 of 2 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Grant # GM-07256-09, 1 of 3 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Grant # GM-07256-09, 2 of 3 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Grant # GM-07256-09, 3 of 3 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Grant # GM-07256-10 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Grant # GM-07256-18, 1 of 3 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Grant # GM-07256-18, 2 of 3 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Grant # GM-07256-18, 3 of 3 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Harvard Search Committee (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - ICSU, 1 of 3 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - ICSU, 2 of 3 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - ICSU, 3 of 3 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - International Union of Biochemists, 1 of 3 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - International Union of Biochemists, 2 of 3 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - International Union of Biochemists, 3 of 3 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - International Union of Biochemists Congress, 1967; 1 of 3 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - International Union of Biochemists Congress, 1967; 2 of 3 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - International Union of Biochemists Congress, 1967; 3 of 3 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - IUPAC and Other Unions, 1 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - IUPAC and Other Unions, 2 of 2 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Japan 1967 Congress (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Lederberg, Dr. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Medical Advisory Board Hebrew University (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - M.D. PhD Seminar, 1973-1974 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - National Academy, 1 of 4 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - National Academy, 2 of 4 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - National Academy, 3 of 4 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - National Academy, 4 of 4 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - National Academy of Sciences National Committee, 1 of 2 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - National Academy of Sciences National Committee, 2 of 2 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - NATO Fellowships (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - National Institute of Health (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - NIH Grant #G7-07256-07 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - NIH Grants, 1960-1965; 1 of 3 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - NIH Grants, 1960-1965; 2 of 3 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - NIH Grants, 1960-1965; 3 of 3 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - NIH Grants, 1970-1972; 1 of 3 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - NIH Grants, 1970-1972; 2 of 3 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - NIH Grants, 1970-1972; 3 of 3 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - National Science Foundation Grant (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Nichols, Rodney W. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Organic and Biochemistry Committee Minutes, 1 of 4 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Organic and Biochemistry Committee Minutes, 2 of 4 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Organic and Biochemistry Committee Minutes, 3 of 4 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Organic and Biochemistry Committee Minutes, 4 of 4 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Organic and Biochemistry Committee Curriculum (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Organic and Biochemistry Committee Examinations (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Organic and Biochemistry Committee Reading List (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Organic and Biochemistry Committee Report 1965 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Reproductive Biology (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Room 611 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Dr. Seitz, 1 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Seitz, 2 of 2 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - 6th International Congress Plenary Lectures (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - 6th International Congress of Biochemistry (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - 7th International Congress Travel Awards (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Spector (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Staff Candidates, 1962; 1 of 3 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Staff Candidates, 1962; 2 of 3 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Staff Candidates, 1962; 3 of 3 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Students, 1 of 2 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Students, 2 of 2 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Structure and Function of Enzymes (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Manuscripts, 1950-1975; 5; 3.52 Cubic Feet
  Includes drafts, some correspondence and notes.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by title of paper, most not dated.
  - Active Site One-Crestfield, 1963 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Active Site Two-Crestfield, 1963; 1 of 2 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Active Site Two-Crestfield, 1963; 2 of 2 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Alkylation Paper, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Amino Acids Papers (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Automatic Fraction Collector (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Blood (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Chromatography, 1 of 3 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Chromatography, 2 of 3 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Chromatography, 3 of 3 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Crestfield Reduction (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Crestfield, 1 of 2 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Crestfield, 2 of 2 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Cystetic Acid-Moore, 1962 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Cyanate Paper (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Cystinuria, 1 of 2 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Cystinuria, 2 of 2 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Histidine and Urea (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - L-Alanine and l-Serine (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Leucine, Valine Charts, 1 of 2 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Leucine, Valine Charts, 2 of 2 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Methionine and Iodoacetate (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Methods in Enzymology, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Metnionine in RNAse (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - N-Monosubstituted Histidines, 1 of 2 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - N-Monosubstituted Histidines, 2 of 2 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Pepsin, 1 of 3 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Pepsin, 2 of 3 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Pepsin, 3 of 3 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Phenylacet (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - RNAse and Iodoacetate, 1958; 1 of 3 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - RNAse and Iodoacetate, 1958; 2 of 3 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - RNAse and Iodoacetate, 1958; 3 of 3 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Schultz, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Scientific American, 1960; 1 of 3 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Scientific American, 1960; 2 of 3 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Scientific American, 1960; 3 of 3 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Smyth RNAse Paper, 1962; 1 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Smyth RNAse Paper, 1962; 2 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Smyth-RNAse 11-18 Sequence, 1 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Smyth-RNAse 11-18 Sequence, 2 of 2 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Streptococcal Proteinase, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Streptococcal Proteinase - Gerwin (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Streptococcal Proteinase - Liu (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Streptococcal Proteinase - Liu, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 1)